Karen A. Largent

610-209-6865 | kalargent@gmail.com Github: https://github.com/kalargent

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/karen-largent/

Portfolio: www.karenlargent.com

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Seasoned software professional and rising Full Stack Engineer who brings deep experience in identifying and defining product features and enhancements. Proven professional record building and leading agile teams, and delivering quality product functionality that strengthens products in the market.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Languages/Libraries: JavaScript, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS, HTML, CSS, MySQL/Sequelize, Mongo/Mongoose, Handlebars, PassportJS, BcryptJS, Moment, Passport-JWT
- UI Frameworks: Bootstrap, Materialize
- Databases: SQL, MongoDB
- Deployment: Heroku, GitHub Pages
- Version Control: Git
- Software: MacOS, Visual Studio Code, Atlassian Jira and Confluence, Microsoft Team Foundation Server(TFS), ProductBoard, Asana

RECENT PROJECTS

Sarge

This is an exercise tracker aimed at Crossfitters to help them track personal records. Users can register, login and track lifts. The deployed version reflects the MVP, and my team continues to update and add new features daily. GitHub: http://bit.ly/31wOPuT | Deployed: http://bit.ly/2qvuwZB

- Uses Bcrypt to encrypt the user's password, and PassportJS to authenticate username/password combinations
- Uses JSON Web Tokens (JWTs) to ensure that the user is authorized to access protected routes

Memory Game

Octocat themed memory game. To win, don't click the same image more than once.

GitHub: http://bit.ly/2BuZovC | Deployed: http://bit.ly/2MxpCny

• First project created with ReactJS

Eat Da Burger

Allows users to move burgers to and from different lists to indicate when one is eaten or on the menu.

GitHub: http://bit.ly/31u1ypB | Deployed: http://bit.ly/2J8MrMd

• NodeJS, MySQL, ExpressJS, Handlebars, Hand-coded Object Relational Mapper (ORM)

Site Scraper

Scrapes a website for articles, allows users to save articles to favorites, view favorites, and add notes.

GitHub: http://bit.ly/2Bv8jNz | Deployed: http://bit.ly/2MvQ6Wd

• NodeJS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, AJAX, MongoDB, ExpressJS, Mongoose, Handlebars

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Relay Network | Radnor, PA Product Manager

December 2017 - May 2019

- Identified and specify product features and requirements with Epics and User Stories
- Improved development throughput by guiding a small agile team of engineers through a transition from Scrum to Kanban
- Focused on minimum viable product to shorten delivery cycles and improve feedback loops on new features and enhancements
- Acted as scrum master, running regular ceremonies and removing roadblocks

Ring Solutions, formerly Zonoff, Inc. | Malvern, PA Senior Product Manager

March 2017 - December 2019

- Elicited and documented the user stories for the user flow to arm and disarm a DIY home security project
- Defined features for an internal support portal that enabled CS agents to resolve customer issues quickly and efficiently and worked with an Agile development team to complete the portal in time for the products to hit the shelf, against aggressive deadlines
- Mapped current CS processed in an effort to identify opportunities for improvement
- Collaborated with CS leadership to open and staff a 100-seat call center in three months, including purchasing, space design
- Designed and implemented a training program and successfully trained 100+ new hires in 5 months

Zonoff, Inc. | Malvern, PA Senior Product Manager

March 2017 - December 2017

- Completed competitive analysis and proposed roadmap items based on research. Developed initial business cases that opened the product into new markets
- Worked with the business, architects, development, and QA to author epics and user stories. Continuously define and iterate on those artifacts during grooming and within sprints
- Functioned as primary contact to multiple clients to gather requirements for customizing and branding Zonoff's Z1 platform to meet their needs
- Supported and mentored 5 development teams simultaneously during sprints to clarify acceptance criteria and close gaps, and identify and triage blockers

EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development, University of Pennsylvania, 2019 Certified Scrum Product Owner (CSPO), Scrum Alliance Bachelor of Arts, English Literature, The Pennsylvania State University